{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Nylon-6 is manufactured from", "opta": "caprolactum.", "optb": "adipic   acid   and   hexamethylene diamine.", "optc": "maleic anhydride and hexamethylene diamine.", "optd": "sebasic acid  and hexamethylene diamine.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Caprolactum, a raw material for the manufacture of nylon-6, is produced from", "opta": "phenol", "optb": "naphthalene", "optc": "benzene", "optd": "pyridine", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The monomer of poly vinyl chloride (PVC) is", "opta": "chloroethene", "optb": "ethylene dichloride", "optc": "ethyl chloride", "optd": "chloroform", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Buna-S is also known as", "opta": "teflon", "optb": "PTFE", "optc": "SBR", "optd": "polycrylates", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Neoprene is chemically known as", "opta": "polybutandiene", "optb": "styrene butadiene rubber (SBR)", "optc": "polyurethane", "optd": "poly chloroprene", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Lavatory cisterns are normally made of", "opta": "expanded polystyrene", "optb": "saturated polyester", "optc": "perspex", "optd": "PVC", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Plasticisers are added to synthetic plastics to", "opta": "impart flexibility.", "optb": "improve workability during fabrication.", "optc": "develop new improved properties not present in the original resin.", "optd": "all (a), (b) and (c).", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Cellulose is the main contituent of most __________ fibres.", "opta": "acrylic", "optb": "spandex", "optc": "synthetic", "optd": "natural", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "__________ resins are produced by the condensation polymerisation of formaldehyde with urea or melamine.", "opta": "Epoxy", "optb": "Amino", "optc": "Alkyd", "optd": "Phenolic", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "__________ tubes are good substitude for human blood vessels onrheart by-pass operation.", "opta": "PVC", "optb": "Polythene", "optc": "Teflon/dacron", "optd": "Polystyrene", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Natural rubber is obtained from latex, which is a colloidal dispersion of rubber in water. Which of the following is used as a coagulant in latex ?", "opta": "Ammonium alum", "optb": "Potassium alum", "optc": "both a & b", "optd": "neither a nor b", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Automobile steering wheels are normally made of", "opta": "cellulose acetate", "optb": "cellulose nitrate", "optc": "PVC", "optd": "high density polythene", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a cross linked polymer, the monomeric units are linked together to constitute a three dimensional network. Which of the following is a cross-linked polymer ?", "opta": "Bakelite (phenol formaldehyde)", "optb": "Polyester", "optc": "Polythene", "optd": "Nylon-6", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "90% of the caprolactum is converted to nylon-6 on its condensation polymerisation in the reactor maintained at a temperature of __________ \u00b0C.", "opta": "-5", "optb": "10-30", "optc": "250-280", "optd": "500-600", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Out of all the elastomers, natural rubber has the longest elongation range & flexibility of the order of __________ percent.", "opta": "1-1000", "optb": "1000-1500", "optc": "1500-2000", "optd": "2000-2500", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following low molecular weight (<104 ), soft & waxy polymer is used in chewing gum ?", "opta": "Cellulose acetate", "optb": "Polyvinyl acetate", "optc": "Thiokol", "optd": "PVC", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Buna-S is a __________ material.", "opta": "fibrous", "optb": "plastic", "optc": "resinous", "optd": "rubbery", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Zeigler - Natta catalyst (AlR3 - AlCl3) is used in the polymerisation of", "opta": "vinyl acetate", "optb": "vinyl chloride", "optc": "propylene", "optd": "styrene", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Due to its excellent permeability to air/gas and oxidation resistance, the tubes of automobile tyres is made of", "opta": "cold SBR", "optb": "butyl rubber", "optc": "Bunai N", "optd": "Buna S", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Neoprene is a", "opta": "monomer", "optb": "synthetic rubber", "optc": "polyester", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The main use of butadiene is", "opta": "as a plasticiser for unsaturated polyester.", "optb": "in the manufacture of synthetic rubber.", "optc": "as an anti-skimming agent in paint.", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Mastication of rubber means", "opta": "its softening.", "optb": "a treatment to retard its deterioration due to oxidation.", "optc": "improving its curing rate.", "optd": "depression of its freezing point.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Polymethyl methacrylate (PMMA) is known as", "opta": "bakelite", "optb": "teflon", "optc": "perspex", "optd": "nylon-6", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Reaction of dimethyl terephthalate (DMT) and ethylene glycol produces", "opta": "nylon-6", "optb": "dacron", "optc": "polyester", "optd": "PVC", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Tubeless tyres are made of __________ rubber, which is a co-polymer of isoprene & isobutylene.", "opta": "nitrile", "optb": "silicone", "optc": "neoprene", "optd": "butyl", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Density of high density polythene is about __________ gm/c.c.", "opta": "1.18", "optb": "1.05", "optc": "0.95", "optd": "0.99", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Vinyl flooring is done using __________ sheets.", "opta": "polypropylene", "optb": "PVC", "optc": "polythene", "optd": "polyvinyl acetate", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Thiokol is nothing but", "opta": "polysulphide rubber", "optb": "polyamide fibre", "optc": "engineering plastic", "optd": "exponded polystyrene", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Transistor parts and refrigerator components are normally made of", "opta": "polystyrene", "optb": "polyester", "optc": "high density polythene", "optd": "polyurathane", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Dacron (or terylene) fibres as compared to nylon fibres have", "opta": "better heat & acid resistant properties.", "optb": "poorer resistance to alkalis.", "optc": "poorer dyeability.", "optd": "all (a), (b) and (c).", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Orlan fibre which is used as a wool sub stitute is", "opta": "an amorphous polymer.", "optb": "a natural polymeric fibre.", "optc": "polyacrylonitrile.", "optd": "polymethylmethacrylate (PMMA).", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Neoprene is the trade name of", "opta": "polyurethane", "optb": "phenol formaldehyde", "optc": "polychlorophrene", "optd": "styrene butadiene rubber (SBR)", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Trade name of __________ is neoprene.", "opta": "polychloroprene", "optb": "polyisoprene", "optc": "polytetraflouroethylene", "optd": "poly vinyl acetate", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "SBR is produced by the copolymerisation of butadiene & styrene by employing emulsion polymerisation. The weight ratio of styrene and butadiene is maintained at", "opta": "1:3", "optb": "3:1", "optc": "1:2", "optd": "2:1", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Dacron is a/an", "opta": "polyester", "optb": "unsaturated polyester", "optc": "polyamide", "optd": "inorganic polymer", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Starting material for the production of SBR is", "opta": "ethyl alcohol", "optb": "ethylene", "optc": "both (a) & (b)", "optd": "neither (a) nor (b)", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is a copolymer ?", "opta": "PVC", "optb": "Bakelite", "optc": "Polythene", "optd": "Teflon", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Fillers such as zinc oxide and carbon black are added to the crude natural rubber before vulcanisation in order to improve its", "opta": "elasticity", "optb": "strength", "optc": "plasticity", "optd": "weathering characteristics", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The organic acid monomer in nylon 66 is", "opta": "sebasic acid", "optb": "terephthalic acid", "optc": "adipic acid", "optd": "benzoic acid", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Neoprene which is used for making shoe heels & belts is superior to natural rubber in its stability to aerial oxidation and resistance to oils & other solvents. The monomer used for making neoprene is", "opta": "chloroethane", "optb": "chlorophrene", "optc": "isoprene", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The synthetic fibres produced from __________ are known as rayon.", "opta": "lignin", "optb": "cellulose", "optc": "polyamides", "optd": "ethylene glycol", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Peptizers like aromatic mercaptans (e.g. thiophenes) are added in rubber to", "opta": "protect rubber goods from attack by oxygen & ozone present in the atmosphere.", "optb": "reduce its viscosity to permit easier processing.", "optc": "reduce the time of vulcanisation and quantity of vulcanising agent.", "optd": "increase its viscosity.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Visco-elastic behaviour exhibited by plastics is a __________ like behaviour.", "opta": "solid", "optb": "liquid", "optc": "combination of solid & liquid", "optd": "neither solid nor liquid", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is generally not used as eord for synthetic rubber tyre casing ?", "opta": "Dacron", "optb": "Nylon", "optc": "Cellulose", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "__________ is not a polyester fibre.", "opta": "Terylene", "optb": "Dacron", "optc": "Nylon", "optd": "Polyacrylonitrite", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Nitrile rubber is produced by the polymerisation of", "opta": "acrylonitrile & butadiene.", "optb": "acrylonitrile & styrene.", "optc": "isobutylene & isoprene.", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Celluloid is", "opta": "cellulose acetate", "optb": "regenerated cellulose", "optc": "cellulose nitrate", "optd": "cellulose acetate butyrate", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Styrene butadiene rubber (SBR) as compared to natural rubber has", "opta": "poor tensile strength.", "optb": "poorer resistance.", "optc": "greater amount of heat build up heavy loading.", "optd": "all (a), (b) ana (c).", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following polymers has the tendency of decomposing before melting ?", "opta": "Polystyrene", "optb": "Nylon", "optc": "PVC", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following polymers belong to the class of formaldehyde resin ?", "opta": "Melamine resins", "optb": "Teflon", "optc": "Dacron", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}